like it's almost automatic yeah I go to
the shower ideas are coming with
me that's that's almost like an
automatic thing so that that's true and
and and and Elmer gate Dr Elmer Gates
found out that same thing wow that's
that's powerful so when tell me a little
bit about your businesses and and the
things that you've done you know cuz you
have a list of accomplishments but like
what what what type of business have you
run well I tell you one of the first
ones man and this is literally how it
happened I couldn't make this up man you
know I I used to um just basically get
goods and I I sold things on the Vans
work tour which is like a rock tour that
tours all over the United States 45
dates and two and a half months and then
all of a sudden man I would get these
products that I would buy from LA and
then I noticed the same people that were
selling me the products would also show
up at some of the same events and sell
the product for a third of the price so
I'm like hold on you're selling me a
product for wholesale and then you're
coming out and compe against me no so my
buddy and I got tired of it and he
literally called me one day and said hey
man here has a job as a computer
programmer and he had a friend that was
from Hong Kong and he said hey man my
man is going back to Hong Kong for a
visit he said we can come over with him
and he'll show us around now keep in
mind this this guy is going back to Hong
Kong is a computer program he's not even
in business so I'm like what the heck is
he going to show us so I said you know
what weap Faith again next thing you
know I go to the wife and said uh I
think I'll be going to Hong
Kong but Hong and literally maybe three
weeks after that conversation I'm on a
plane and I'm going to Hong Kong my man
and we B this guy basically gave us an
hour tour he met us at the airport I
didn't even get to take the bags off I'm
walking around Hong Kong with this big
freaking backpack on and he show us a
couple trade shows and and then he says
great there you go now I have to go back
to my wife but little did he let us know
that Hong Kong will wasn't where the
business was deep in coming this CH was
where the business was so we had to go
get a visa and we had to leave our stuff
at the hotel of Hong Kong and we took a
4-Hour train ride into shinen China and
then this place called Guang Joo and we
had to learn it all over again we had to
move around with a business card because
all the businesses were in cantones and
I can't Cantonese so get get cabs for
men who don't even speak English and say
hey uh take us here or point at the car
hey and then he take us there and
says and you just pray that the building
he
that is he actually building you need to
go to I mean it man I couldn't make this
up man it's it's it was the most intense
thing so I started business off in the
most fearful way at the beginning most
people probably would do that at the end
but I think that was a great thing
because it kind of set everything up so
that's how I really started it it
started from there wow like do that that
I would be you know I can tell you like
I I love welcome to the hustle Zone this
is RP to God AKA The Wizard AKA Ry Perez
uh owner and founder of bowai creative
uh this is a that we we donate uh free
websites to entrepreneurs uh with
disabilities so if you buy if you buy a
website uh through us we donate a
website to someone that you know has
experienced uh challenges Etc uh today
welcome to the hustle Zone today is a
really awesome day uh just because you
know I've I've I've the Our Guest he is
someone that Tru inspires me you know we
met uh a maybe like I would say 6 months
ago and he has demonstrated to me you
know what a a successful business owner
is and he's a he's a Serial entrepreneur
I mean this guy has you know several
businesses and you know his kids are
entrepreneurs which is amazing and um
you know I I'll tell you an experience
that I had with
him I I started when I started m company
bowai creative I started you know this
was just something that I did because uh
I just at the time I had
U I had left a relationship with my with
my ex fiance and I was
broke so I said you know what I'm just
going to do this business thing and I'm
going to win so I decided to start the
business and
what was interesting is that I held on
to the business as a
crutch you know it kept me
busy it really didn't give me time to
really focus on my personal life and
actually to give me time to actually
focus on myself and my few interactions
with
Abdul Abdul started asking me
questions and Abdul is very you know
he's he's famous for really digging into
people's you know lives and really
asking hard pressed questions that you
can't deny but you kind of shrug off
because you don't want to hear the truth
and he pretty much made me realize that
he said you know he was talking about
like you know the eth and I read the e-
myth you know creating systems and and
and and whatnot but
Abdul he you know may just made me
realize that I was kind of doing doing
this business to kind of
cure you know some of the things that I
was suffering at the time just some of
the pain and it was like three years of
pain to be honest with you and you know
he and I didn't really need to be I
didn't really need to be the the the
accountant the uh I didn't need to be
the uh the admin the administration I
didn't need to be the graphic designer
and the web developer but I took on all
those jobs because I just wanted to to
do it because I needed something to do
and that was a big
realization so he helped me see that I
need to make this into a business I need
to actually start making my business
into a business I know all about it and
you know and that's what I've been doing
these last several months is just re I I
changed my focus changed my logo changed
a lot of things and changed my Direction
so that I can walk away in 2017 I plan
in January 1st to to uh uh give my
business put my business in someone
else's hands and that was kind of due to
uh Abdul sparking that flame so I want
to I want to have a have a big
welcome I want you guys to to stand up
and
applaud you know Abdul Muhammad how are
you doing my friend you're gonna have to
unmute
yourself I'm great Ryan can you hear me
yeah I can hear you so before we get
started I gotta do it man you know I
gotta do it yeah yeah yeah
so welcome to the hustles
out I like that I love it I love it so
let me get my camera
straight so how are you doing my friend
man I can't complain man just just glad
glad to be here to be honest that's
awesome so what did you think about that
introduction I mean you know it it takes
a lot of guts for someone to to admit
that you know what you know my thinking
was wrong and you you definitely help me
just wake up realize that this was I was
doing a lot of the you know earlier on
in the year I was doing this for
personal reasons and not for the not
even for the the the best n for the best
uh um what's the word it wasn't even for
the best interest of my business I was
just kind of doing it to kind of keep
myself
happy well you know Ryan man first let
me say this
entrepreneurs and I know a lot of people
out there do different things but my
opinion are some of the bravest people
known to man because basically you're
telling yourself I'm G to get up every
day and I'm going to make
money
and you see what I'm saying just the
thought of that that I'm going to create
money and cuz most people show up at
their their jobs or whatever they do on
a daily basis and that money making how
to make it is already taken care of so
all they do is just show up and say hey
in two weeks I want something but
entrepreneurs you can't do that you have
to build that system and come up with
something in order and let your reward
be money on the other end it's it's a
hard task man that's right that's right
and you've demonstrated that you've made
money I mean you got a lot of money that
you're gonna have to send some money
over over to uh to uh to Calgary Alberta
I would love to have some of that money
uh
so Abdul so you you are an author yeah
you are you have been on reality TV uhuh
you have over
25,000 uh subscribers on YouTube you
have uh well YouTube and Facebook
combined combined and um but you have a
successful YouTube channel because when
I first met you I checked you out I I I
always check out people and stuff and
very successful and ie open a lot of
your your videos are really fruitful and
and whatnot so you're also you were also
in the
military yes so you have a back you have
a foundation of of discipline and and
just staying steadfast to your goals and
your Visions would you say that yeah man
yeah I I have to be that way too because
one thing you didn't mention was I have
ADHD so I have to have structure in my
life you have to have structure in your
life yeah I I got ADHD too or I don't
know I'm just hyperactive I need to be
like keep myself going and what not but
the structure is so important especially
for guys like us because that that could
be a reason why you know some of us
would fail because we're we're not
consistent and I have a a secret to tell
you man this is a secret but
most entrepreneurs have
ADHD can you back that
up yes by just by Behavior alone
disorganized uh the ability to come up
with ability to problem solve many
different ideas um most entrepreneurs I
come in contact with has had maybe 10 to
20 business ideas we get bored very
easily the stimulation that self of of
leaving the job and actually waking up
and and making something happen and that
stimulation that that activity is
something a n adhdp person would run
away from but yeah I mean you look at
any businessman you know um 8 stepen
sided and look and see do they have it
nine times out of 10 they would have it
like my man uh Virgin Records Virgin
Mobile dyslexia ADHD I mean the list
just goes down the line I mean it's it's
a common thing and it's not and I want
to say too it's not a
disability it's just that we may not
know how to use his
superpowers
totally totally I I I can agree with you
with that I and I I I've discovered some
ways of how to enhance my because I I
really think my dyslexia is a dis is
it's an
ability uh I I use I say a disability
sometimes just so that people can
understand that you know it does like in
certain environments like it can be
really hard but I realized that for me
being dyslexic I need to find different
ways of absorbing
information which is amazing you know
because I could get to the root of a
problem where as you know some people
that are linear thinkers that just read
read the book they may not understand it
because I have to check few sources
before I commit to the knowledge that I
learn so you know that's kind of
something that uh I think is an ability
of mine and and it really keeps me keeps
me sharp but also gives people a
different you know like I can provide
different
perspectives but but but right you're
struggling through it think about all
the
people that what they say the average
American doesn't read another book after
high
school so that means that gave up on
learning anything that looks like
learning I'm staying far away from it I
suffered through that through high
school and college I don't want to mess
with me anymore but you're like no even
though I have my setbacks I still want
to learn so you have I and I think you
if I'm not mistaken I think you have to
listen to things at a higher speed
that's right in order to obtain that
information superhuman speed like I I
could read a book literally half a day
like a you know that could be any novel
it take me about half a day to read
through all of that and know it
understand it and commit it to me
yeah which is you know which I you know
at the time I didn't I didn't know it
because every time I listen to it I'm
like I just don't get it so I I you know
and I just wanted to get to the point
and I'm like you know you know you have
a hyperactive mind so I just started
cranking it up cranking it up and it's
like I'm like oh yeah yeah you know
Stephen cvy I'm like oh seven habits so
being proactive I get it I get it I get
it so yeah it really helped it it aided
a lot of my learning and I tried so many
different ways of learning but uh I had
to learn because you know what even
though being an entrepreneur and maybe
you can agree with this or not did you
go to school for
entrepreneurism well I went to school
for international business that's what
my major is in okay so you understand
school is important no matter what
anyone says school is important right
it's just not it's not going to get you
you know don't think that it's a a
school is just because you get a diploma
you're going to be successful but you
know I I I still I still read I read
textbooks because I want to keep my
brain you know I still want to learn as
much as I can you know but what you're
teaching me is how to
delegate right that delegation is
important so we're going to get into all
of that um um my the fans of the hustle
Zone would uh would get mad at me if I
didn't ask this question and I ask this
with everybody that comes on to the the
the hustle Z what is your story usually
the most important like the thing about
the hustle zone is that we capture the
spirit of the entrepreneur we want to we
want to get to know the man behind the
entrepreneur you know what how did you
start where did you begin you know and
what what caused you to become the man
that you are today so you know I'm GNA
flip that question on you so like what
is your
story so as you know right we were
talking earlier so I'm a member of this
5 a.m book club where we and it the name
what it said what the name is is what we
do so at 5 am in the morning central
time we were on there
talking about books and accountability
and this question came up about when did
you know like when did you know you were
an entrepreneur and for me um I went to
this party man and I never forget it was
in Memphis Tennessee and uh you know in
high school everybody's dressing nobody
has money but somehow these kids have
these fancy clothes and this day I had
on some bull crap man I'm talking about
like bell bottom blue jeans a ha Wan
shirt I I I didn't come for money so
what what I what was on sale is what I
had and man I remember I had pins in my
pants at the bottom people on
laugh I'm just like man this is
embarrassing so I'm standing against the
wall standing next to bushes trying to
hide
these right but I told myself this will
never happen again if I show up to these
parties again I need to make my own
money so literally that next week uh the
friends that I met over there during the
summer I said uh I said no I said let's
go your mom has a lawn mower let's get
that lawn mower and let's knock on these
doors and ask see people can REM their
yard and I don't know why I said
$20 next thing I know every door that
we're knocking on everybody saying yes
yes yes next thing you know we have
about 50 accounts and now we're all more
yards my man told Joo is using his mom's
lawnmower I'm using my aunt's lawnmower
another guy's using his mom's lawnmower
and now we have a business and next we
went from some bull crap at the party so
now everybody has money in their pockets
and that was kind of like my first start
I guess you can say with
entrepreneurship okay so did you ever
have any U so was that the wakeup call
for you because I guess everyone has
different wakeup calls some people their
wakeup call is a result of pain you know
of some Misfortune you know mine was me
breaking up with my my ex fiance you
know um did you have anything like that
or was it just the fact that you went to
the party with bell bottoms on with pins
in them and that was just enough for you
to get your your button to Gear Well I'm
G ask this question to you
Ryan are you are you a good
employee hell no
you see you see how that just flowed out
your Tong like that like you know how
some people said you know I I I receive
employees the month you know like great
if they had an award for Worse employees
the month I probably would win that
award I'm just I found out very early
I'm not a great employee so if this is
going to be my future I'm GNA be eating
top Ren for the rest of my life so I
said I gotta get out of this Lane as
fast as possible
and if you study entrepreneurs you find
out that a lot of them work good
employees I mean I've heard
entrepreneurs say things like I went to
a job for two days and I learn in two
days this is not for me I'm like two
days that's all you mean you didn't give
it two years like no two days that's all
I know and and that's that was my story
man so I had to say no I gotta find a
better way so that's how I got an
entrepreneu so so tell me tell me like
what what kind of employee were
you well like I'm the type of guy I I
say I have performance anxiety like I'm
the guy if I'm bouncing the basketball
down the court and then and let's say
it's like 200 people watching and
everybody says make it make it make it I
would go up and and throw the ball up on
the backboard and and bounce it off so
hard and it wouldn't even hit it
wouldn't make the best because in my
mind I'm thinking like don't miss it
don't miss it don't miss it don't miss
it I have to be alone
in almost like a Buddhist mug state to
work I don't want nobody around me I
don't want because because here's why I
want to make a lot of mistakes and I
want to make those mistakes without
judgment because in in order to get your
sweet spot you're going to have to make
mistakes so I'm not going to be this
perfectionist or this this myth or you
know that kind of thing I want to make
mistakes uh where it's allow right so
that's kind of like why I like creating
in my lab and working
alone I'm the same way I so I I take it
you're an
introvert yeah I didn't find it out I
thought for the longest time I thought I
was an extrovert but I am a true
introvert yeah people TR
me you saw the express dra they dra yeah
I feel you I'm the same way because not
that I don't like people I love talking
but I love talking behind the camera I
just don't want you talking in my home
you know what I mean I don't want to be
sitting here entertaining um um you know
when I'm when I especially when my mind
is on the grind like when I when I want
to build something if I want to create I
kind of need that space my man cave to
just do what I got to do with so I can
keep that energy up but but let me
correct that a little bit because I
don't want people walk away from this
say like man you don't like people
that's rude no it's not that like if you
come up to me and you're and here's this
is how your conversation goes and I put
this on a post not too long ago like if
I say hey I want to go to Mexico and you
say something like man that's dangerous
you can get
kidnapped my mind is already shut off
you you're in a whole another Lane I'm
not listening anymore if you say like
man that weather man I tell you man you
know it it's the things that you talk
about if you're talking about things and
other people I'm I'm
yawning that's that's not a conversation
that's going to benefit any of us that's
right and and to be honest this is what
a majority of people talk about our
things I need something that's going to
stimulate me man that's right right yeah
that's right so you know speaking of
which um you have a lot of things that
uh that you've done now tell me a little
bit about your book how to find your
passion yeah well you know it's so funny
because I was actually going to write a
business book
and I don't even know how I started
writing and said I want to write a book
how to find your passion now and you
know they say there are no mistakes in
life when I started my YouTube channel
the first video I did
was about I was doing a rebuttal like a
a review on something and that was just
to build my nerve up to say I want to do
a YouTube video but the second video I
made was called how to find your passion
and it's so funny how we do these things
in life and and life gives us
Clues and if you go back and look at it
the clues are all around you but we we I
don't know if we're not ready for them
yet but they're always there we haven't
seen them so there was Clues all around
me that I'm I'm the passion of I would I
would literally talk to people and I'll
see they're all excited about this thing
or like they're sitting there drawing a
picture because they're bored and the
picture look like it could walk off the
page and I'm like holy crap you should
be a cartoonist you should be a graphic
artist you should be this like no no no
I'm happy being a banker I'm happy being
a teller I'm happy being a a lawn
service guy and then the conversation
was like are you freaking crazy like
anybody can be that but very few people
can be this that's a and you know I'm
not trying to get religious by
mentioning his name but that's a
god-given gift that's bigger than you
like I've been drawing the same stick
figure since third grade I'm not
Advanced so I am not an artist but the
people who are you got to be using
that it's it I I I believe in the law
there's a reason for everything if I
walk if I was on this interview right
now which I am and I got up and left you
probably would say hey where you going
oh why did you do that and if I come
back and say you know what I I really
don't know you'll be like man dude's
been drinking or something like how how
does he not know he just because there's
a reason for everything right so that's
that's that's my philosophy so um when
it comes to finding your passion you
know a lot of people what what is what
are the reasons that prevent people from
finding their passions like what are the
things that are holding people back yeah
themselves one the courage because
really most people aren't jumpers
entrepreneurs going back to the bravest
people in life most people are not going
to risk the word risk is like that's not
even
aul you're saying like like I give
example of a man from the I want to get
this make sure I'm getting this right
the Roland Stones who actually went to
school to be an
account and dropped out his
college and said hey Mom I'm going to
start a band and I'm sure a lot of moms
and dads heard that conversation you're
like you need to tell me you're in a
freaking college that I've saved my life
for and you're going to leave this
college to join some hippie band but the
Rolling Stones have been around now and
they're in their 70s all the the members
are still alive and they're still
touring the uh the world you can't do
anything like that if you don't love
it you know like some people people say
hey when are you going to retire well
Warren Buffett is 90 in his 90s he
hasn't retired you don't retire when you
love what you're doing because you would
die if you're not able to do it you
would die in the inside so everybody is
I want everybody hear this if you're
walking you're breathing you you're
existing you have something inside of
you that you do better than the people
around you and that's the thing that you
should be using
to make a
limit wo that's pretty deep you know
because it's I think we all know the
truth I think that we all have a spirit
within that kind of tells us that hey
I'm not happy here you know hey I can do
this you know some people are like
singing
like I can
sing you know I remember when I was a
kid I would walk uh you know I hated
school and when I walk home I would be
singing in my head and I would be
writing songs and I've even produced
songs that I wrote when I was like seven
you know songs that I've never forgotten
but that is an innate ability that I
have you know and also graphic design
and stuff like that so you know I think
you know just to paraphrase what you're
saying it's like you know we just need
to be in touch with ourselves because
would you agree that there's some of us
that really don't know ourselves that
don't really want to get in touch with
ourselves Man Okay so let's stay there
for a second yeah I want to ask you
another question Ryan all these
questions you have a son let's say
you're you're you're the mother of your
child said hey I'm G to watch the kid
would you travel to Russia by
yourself
uh Russia yeah probably but by yourself
or would you take someone with you by
myself you you would do it
yeah I I I knew the answer would be yes
because you're an entrepreneur you've
already taking the risk most people
can't even go to a restaurant by
themselves I know that's crazy you know
what's so funny man I I'm at a
restaurant one time and I'm just
relaxing and I notic these people keep
looking at the table I'm like what the
heck you guys looking at like what the
hell got something my face or something
like what's going on
and then finally said man hey man you
can come over and sit with us and and
the first thing I'm thinking like man I
don't I don't do that that stuff I don't
I'm in and women I'm not you know I'm
not but you know why he's asking me that
he's asking me that because he's like
for him to see me at the table alone
that must mean I'm a lonely
guy and when we basically what he's
saying is when we go out we have to go
out in groups and I don't know if you
guys knew this or not but in a group
there's always a leader and that leader
probably would convince other people to
do certain things and somebody in the
group is GNA be left out right so I
learned in the military right away when
I was 17 man and everybody else is 21 I
had to learn to have my own damn fun or
I wasn't going to do anything for the
weekend so I got so good at it that the
guys who were 21 wanted to come with me
because they would hear about the things
that I was just doing so I had to learn
that skill that it's okay to go Al it's
okay to travel along because when you do
those things you learn who you are
inside you learn what you like doing and
do but most people aren't brave enough
to do that most people hate being alone
by themselves do you do you do you do
any meditation like how do you how how
do you prepare yourself for the day
because there's a lot of us that you
know entrepreneurialism like the whole
this way of life is draining and can be
draining at times especially when you're
dealing with certain challenges and uh
you know what how do you deal with your
challenges and how do you keep yourself
centered yeah well okay so this book
club that I'm in which is we do seven
days a week the first thing we do when
we get on if we get on at time we do a
three minute
meditation now I try to before I even
get there I I got into a ritual now of
at 3:45 a.m. in the morning my alarm
clock goes are so I get up grab the
water drink the water and then I
immediately go to the bathtub and I run
bath water run to bath water get inside
and I take I I lay there I have audio
going and then I listen to audio for a
certain time and then I'll listen to
like deac choker and I turn the lights
off everything and I try to get my mind
in the right State because I going tell
you why I do that and I'll be real short
on this one you ever heard of a Gent by
the name of Dr Elmer
Gates yes okay well for the audience
that may have not Dr Elmer Gates was
basically like your I don't want to say
Einstein because he stole some ideas but
he was known at he was hired by
companies to create ideas and the way
that he would do it is his house still
exists in Chevy Chase Maryland he
blacked out all the windows he didn't
have an ounce of light that came in and
he would go in and literally close his
eyes and I don't even know if he knew
what he was doing at this time and there
was one time that he did it and he
always would take a yellow pad in there
and he wrote for like two to three hours
of just ideas and even he's mentioned in
the book thinking gr rich and they they
they showcase him and let him know that
even Napoleon Hill would say I don't
know why it works but when you're when
you're trying to come up with something
before you start your day close your
eyes and what and what people say is
happening is you're you're you're
getting into that Alpha state of mind
right and and and a lot of people have
success with it with Transcendental
Meditation uh whatever it is you got to
quiet the mind the mind is always
constantly going and and busy and stuff
all the the time it's hard to kind of
Center and
focus so you have to start your day off
with quiet and
meditation yeah and I find that when I
sleep when I sleep yeah uh I get whether
I medit or when I sleep I get a lot of
answers like I wake up with Solutions
because like sometimes I I'm like every
day trying to drill at a problem and
trying to figure out a way to like make
myself feel you know at peace but when I
go to sleep or if I take I take showers
I love I I love my showers you know on
you know what I mean and because I think
it's the theta waves or whatever that
are in like with the water hitting the
ground but it gets me going it gets me
thinking about new new ideas that I
don't really necessarily do in my
environment when I'm actually working so
it's like you know having that mental
preparedness every day keeping yourself
centered and I and just what you said
earlier is like not associating yourself
with people that are you know talking
about negativity that kind of keeps
keeps things going you know you know
righty here's what I learned about IDE
about ideas or thinking coming up with
an idea it's almost like picture this
you're in a shower and your homeboy are
outside and you're blowing a
horn and you're like
man I can't go out there and talk to
them I'm in the shower and then they
blow the horn for so long and then all
of a sudden they take
off that's what an idea is you ever had
an idea and then all of a sudden it's
you like holy crap it's good I'm gonna
write that down when I find some paper
and by the time you find the paper it's
gone it's gone yeah but have you noticed
that when you take a shower ideas are
dancing it's like you're at a nightclub
and ideas are all in the dance
room and you just grabbing them that's
an idea an
idea they're all over the place but if
you try to think about something if I
gave you a task now say Ryan I want you
to think of 10 business ideas right now
and you force yourself to think you
probably could come up with three
because now you're forcing the mind do
something so then I learned like ideas
don't come when you force it they come
when you least think about they come
when you're driving on a long trip they
come when you're on the airplane they
come when you're in the shower like it's
almost automatic yeah I go to the shower
ideas are coming with
me that's that's almost like an
automatic thing so that that's true and
and and and Elmer gate Dr Elmer Gates
found out that same thing wow that's
that's powerful so when tell me a little
bit about your businesses and and the
things that you've done you know cuz you
have a list of accomplishments but like
what what what type of business have you
run well I tell you one of the first
ones man and this is literally how it
happened I couldn't make this up man you
know I I used to um just basically get
goods and I I sold things on a Vans work
tour which is like a rock tour that
tours all over the United States 45
dates and two and a half months and then
all of a sudden man I would get these
products that I would buy from LA and
then I noticed the same people that was
selling me the products would also show
up at some of the same events and sell
the product for a third of the price so
I'm like hold on you're selling me a
product for wholesale and then you're
coming out and competing against me NOP
so my buddy and I got tired of it he
literally called me one day and said hey
man he has a job as a computer
programmer and he had a friend that was
from Hong Kong and he said hey man my
man is going back to Hong Kong for a
visit he said we can come over with him
and he'll show us a
like keep in mind this this guy that's
going back to Hong Kong is a computer
programmer he's not even in business so
I'm like what the heck is he going to
show us so I said you know what weap of
Faith again next thing you know I'll go
to the wife and said uh I think I'll be
going to
Hong what H and literally maybe three
weeks after that conversation I'm on a
plane and I'm going to Hong Kong my man
and we B this guy basically gave us an
hour tour he met us at the airport I
didn't even get to take the bags off I'm
walking around Hong Kong with this big
freaking backpack on and he show us a
couple trade shows and then he says
great there you go now I have to go back
to my wife but Lally he let us know that
Hong Kong Willie wasn't where the
business was deep incoming this China
was where the business was so we had to
go get a visa and we had to leave our
stuff at the hotel in Hong Kong and we
took a 4-Hour train ride in the in China
and then this place called Guang Jo and
we had to learn it all over again to
move around with a business card because
all the businesses were in cantones and
I can't read Cantonese so get get cabs
for men who don't even speak English and
say hey uh take us here or point at the
car heyy and then he take us there and
says and you just pray that the build
that
is the act building you need to go to I
mean it man I couldn't make this up man
it's it's it was the most intense theme
so I started business off in the most
fearful way at the beginning most people
probably would do that at the end but I
think that was a great thing because it
kind of set everything up so that's how
I really started it it started from
there wow like that's that that I would
be you know I can tell you like I I love
fear but when I'm in it I'm like you
know I went to South America to visit my
dad for the first time and I was like
just driving down the highway and with
with with cows walking across the street
and you know the cab driver driving like
160 miles hour and there's no seat belts
like they're not allowed to have seat
belts in their cars wow yeah so there's
no seat belts in the car so you're
like you know like over the you're all
thrown over the place because like the
hustle Zone like the hustle
Zone but you know like it but it was but
when you got to your
destination you know you you forgot
about the ride you know and and but I
like I know that the fear I always love
the fear I read this book a long time
ago feel feel the fear and do it anyways
y you know and that's when you know that
you're on the right path because when
you feel that in your stomach that you
know like hey this is cuz you know fear
is like it could be uh excitement like
that feeling that you feel within
yourself is either fear or excitement
like you you could be excited about
something so much that it makes your
brain go all kind of all kind of ways
but you know that must have been a very
interesting trip that you had but you
know so the kind of resiliency that you
you uh uh that you've developed from
that from that experience like what can
you elaborate more on that like how has
that really set you up well I tell you
what man the event before that actually
set me up is is an event that happened
in the military where I went to Somalia
and um I we flew to Somalia and I
remember right before we landed and you
you give me your reaction if you hear
this come over the loud speaker um we
can't land at the moment because they
were shooting planes out of the air in
Somali we can't land at the moment we
have to circle around to make sure uh
the airport is secure before we land at
that moment I look outside the window
there's an Apache helicopter escorting
Us in into the airport woo so I'm
already crapping my pants before I even
land and then when we get there and the
daytime was quiet man you think like man
this is a library like why they s in the
Somaya there Ain no problems here and at
night time man this like freaking
fireworks cuz that's when the fighting
is happening now go to sleep at night
you're in an abandoned um mansion that
the US basically has taken over and
turned it into a military compound and
you have a cut and you hear all this
fighting going in the background go to
sleep it took me about two weeks to go
to
sleep and when I first felt finally went
to sleep I'm like I'm insane how could I
go to sleep and I can not wake up but at
that point where I I really got to the
point where I didn't fear
death that's the ultimate uh fear faer
if that makes sense so everything else
at that point was easy to be
honest cuz once you go down that road
what else are you going to fear
wow that's that's intense yeah tell
that's intense so tell me um what have
you been up to lately like what what are
the things that are driving you and uh
what sort of Ventures do you have going
on okay well I I started a partnership
man with my man Samuel um which is a
marketing genius it's called marketing
strategy tv.com we're going to do these
weekly webinars and um so I I said man I
have to add some value because you know
I could come on here and and get people
to contact me and things like that but I
need a system and and to be honest
out of every entrepreneur that comes in
life you don't have a business until you
have customers that are walking through
your door you may want a business but
you need to have customers coming in on
a regular basis and the way to do that
is that you have to either Master
marketing yourself or you going to hire
somebody that understands marke so what
I did was burn the boats and I said
who's the who's one of the top
influencers in marketing it was Ryan
Dice and I'm taking his certifications
now and I've taken four finished four
and I have four more to go and I have
all the certifications so that's that's
what I'm doing now is kind of putting
the piece together with marketing and
business that makes sense okay that
makes sense so what what like based off
of what you've uh like based off of the
um the course what are some of the
takeaways that uh that we can apply to
our lives like you know cuz a lot of us
are digital you know or we're we're
we're speakers we're entrepreneurs not
really engaging people via social media
and we just don't know what to do like
what would be your advice well they have
this thing they call top of the funnel
activities so you have the top of the
funnel middle of the funnel and bottom
of the funnel bottom of the funnel is
when people pulling out their wallet and
buying things but before you can take
the customer there you have to give them
value so what does that look like
podcast
blogs um videos on
YouTube um video on
Periscope uh giving people value and I
would say this may sound extreme for
some people I would say daily because if
the customers forget about you and
there's so many people out there who are
who are the new the next new
motivational speaker the next new this
they will easily take your place so you
have to hit the marketplace and you have
to continue to give them great value and
keep putting it in their face and then
while you're doing that cuz here's the
here's the most important piece make a
product if you don't have a product and
you just out there giving motivational
talks and you don't have a product
attached to it you don't have a business
you're basically wasting
time being honest you wasting time and
when I start off on YouTube because I
liked it I was just showing up doing
videos because I really didn't have
people to talk to about these subjects
but it turned into a business because
people started saying hey can you give
me some consultation or something like
that so miraculously after doing that
for so long and turned into something
like that but have a product and give
the people value don't just come on
there and sell sell sell buy my product
today no give about 90% of value and ask
them to buy something about 10% of the
time that that's the strategy so that's
one of some of the basic things that you
can do when it comes to marketing M you
were telling me that like you know you
you you realized when you took this
course that you you got you know in the
Caribbean we say you got licks you know
what I mean so like what were the things
that you re that you realized that you
didn't really get before Oh I found out
I knew nothing about marketing um when I
I say very little about marketing this
course basically has been slapping me
around and beating me up and it's good
like for instance I just took a a an
exam right before I came on and you can
take exam five times I literally took it
three times wow it was beating me up and
I was studying the material and
everything and writing down notes I'm
like man this is crazy it was on like
search Eng and
optimization
so yeah but it's good to do things like
that right is you know a lot of people
run from knowledge man if something is
over their head they're like look I
don't want to hear it but when you make
those steps and and fight through it and
get through it then that's why people
get paid the big dollars
these experts because they forc
themselves to get through that
information right so we got to do these
in we got to do these type of things in
business that's right okay so uh Abdul I
just wanted to acknowledge some of the
people that we have in the room uh we
have Susan day we have Kent Johnson he
says Ryan the hustle on I've been uh
catching replays glad to be live awesome
um who Okay Kent says what are your
biggest struggles okay we're we'll do a
a question and answer period um after
our commercial break uh we have Aaron
Adamson guys good to see you guys that's
awesome and then we got Veronica in the
house uh Veronica says giving value
daily and she said buy it now
LOL and then and then Aaron Aaron
Adamson said uh he is here as well so
that's great we just want to acknowledge
you guys and thank you guys for
participating in this in this broadcast
uh we are going to head into a quick uh
o you guys can't see me we're going to
head into a quick commercial break and
we'll be back uh Abdul if you don't mind
to mute yourself for a few minutes and
I'll give you a back
in more people will find the confidence
to reach their
goals a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanagan man who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with
disabilities it gives me a great
pleasure to introduce to you Michael D
Haynes a motivational speaker an
entrepreneur and a businessman Michael
Haynes is doing it all and I absolutely
love it it's the best job I've ever had
in the beginning Haynes admits that he
didn't know how to get his customer
service Consulting business off the
ground and then he met Ryan Perez with
bowai creative for every website that we
sell we donate uh free websites to
entrepreneurs with disabilities the
Calgary based company builds websites
for businesses Haynes knew he needed a
website to promote himself and Perez
knew he had the tools to help we were
always talking about working um um in
the in or doing something for the
disability or for the for people with
disabilities um but we didn't know what
we were going to do and I thought that
this was a great time to um to do
something and and so we invented this
whole initiative like pretty much around
Michael bow tie creative built and
maintains an entire website for hannes
free of charge he um put my ideas into
action and that made my my
job so much
it's an initiative that the four-person
company is proud of it's especially
close to pere's heart because he himself
has dyslexia I paved my own path and
that's why this this this project means
so much to me because I want to help
other people create their paths
so uh Abdul yeah I'm not sure it just
said that it but we're we're still live
though um can you hear
me so uh do yeah I'm not sure it just
hold on one second here
I think Abdul is
frozen hold on one second
here we're having some technical
difficulties will be right back
yeah we lost lost the feed that was
crazy hey that's man sometimes it's good
oh I like that so right now you have
please stand by
yeah man you got some down
back okay so we are we are back okay
folks that was the commercial and um you
guys have you see what like I like to do
this this is my passion I love the
hustle Zone however you know uh we got
to make money somehow and you see how
well uh we put together these hustle
Zone shows so if you want to advertise
your business or you have a commercial
or want me to play like you know up to
three like up to two and a half minute
video um you can definitely do that on
hustle own just please hit me up uh on
my uh uh in my uh DMS and I'll
definitely help you out also like I said
my name is Ryan Perez B uh owner of Bai
creative we donate for every website we
sell we donate a free website to an
entrepreneur with disability uh this is
not just about you know getting you to
buy a website but also if you know
someone that deserves a free website you
know hit us up and and we'll definitely
help them out we have like if you go on
to our website ww. botc creative.com uh
they can fill out a free sign up uh
where they they it's a waiting list and
you know when when there's a free
website available we'll we'll donate one
to them so either way we're going to get
back to so
Abdul got some questions for you
yeah what do you like to do for
fun you know that's an interesting
question man I've actually been told by
people like man what you loosen up a
little bit man all you do this business
up all the time but what they fail to
realize is that's what I find
fun I'm actually I don't think there's
anything wrong with Obsession like you
know now of course if there's drugs or
something like that or alcohol that's
something totally different but um I
love this space man I can't even see
myself doing anything else so I'm I'm
actually
having hold can you hold on one second
here I just got to pause there so ke can
you repeat that one more time the whole
thing or just what just the last part
yeah I I'm actually having fun this this
is a space I'm supposed to be in I love
showing up I don't have to fight the
alarm clock when it goes off
I'm excited about getting up so I'm
actually in my fun zone right now that's
awesome and uh what what's your favorite
dish what do you like to eat oh that's
easy man chicken curry chicken curry
yeah so chicken curry that's uh is that
which where's the curry from that you
like to eat oh good question I'm a fan
of Curry period man so I like Thai
yellow curry Tha green curry Indian
curry um I like the island Cur Curry
I've had some uh some some Curry from
Jamaica U I know you a curry man because
you're from South South America right
yeah well from Guyana my my dad's from
Guyana and my mom's from Trinidad so we
we definitely eat a lot of Curry and and
whatnot Chutney and all kinds of things
out there I like all the variations of
Curry man but uh yeah I'm a big fan of
Curry and uh what's your favorite
television show you have to you know
like we we all I know all entrepreneurs
be like I don't watch television but you
got to watch something sometime so what
what do you like to watch to be honest
man I I know you've heard that a lot
like oh I'm I don't I'm not the guy that
say oh it's Tuesday I need to run and
watch this television doesn't do it for
me Netflix does it for me um now I have
a favorite documentary on um I guess you
can call this a documentary yeah uh Tony
Robbins has one on there called I am not
your
Guru um that's what I'm kind of liking
right now but so I'm more into that man
more into
documentaries yeah I like documentaries
and what's the last book that you read
oh he's so in the book club we just
finished the $100 startup and we're
getting ready it's funny you said it
because we're getting ready to read the
Emil that's starting tomorrow that's one
of the best books on the planet you know
that's the best book you know his
illustrations and him talking about uh
McDonald's us McDonald you know everyone
can build a You Know Better Burger than
McDonald's but a lot of people cannot
duplicate the system that makes those
Burgers yep you know a lot of people get
up and guess every day that's not a
that's not that's not a good thing so
what is one thing that people you know
cuz you know you come online you know
you're motivational coach you know
things of that
nature uh what What's one thing that
people don't know about you
H oh that my birth name isn't
Abdul what's your birth
name now now you set me up to get
bullied
here let me stop ah let me think about
this or I I'll tell you offline let's
just say it starts with a b and it ends
with M the people that knew me of course
um before I converted because I
converted to Islam in 95 so the people
that knew me before they know my name
but uh I just say starts with a B in
what I wonder what that
is I'll give you three chances if you if
you can guess it I'll say yep that's
it starts with a B okay uh and it ends
with an M no that's my last name just
just stick with the first name three
chances on the first Bobby no oh
Boyd
no
uh with a B yep with a
B I gotta Google this
names huh names that start Blain
nope you're
done come on you got to tell the
people this is not for me this is for
them Bradford
Bradford well there nothing wrong with
that because it's Brad it's what's like
what's up oh no no no what's nothing
wrong with but I'm just saying I I keep
certain things out of the out of the
when when did you convert to Islam when
yeah in 95 when I was in the military I
was stationed in Cuba during that time
and what what made you convert you know
what was the thing that
uh it was this guy his name was
naii and to me he was the I've never
seen a guy in my life that dis I'm
talking about you know praying before
the sun comes up five times a day the
way he ate the way he prayed the the
knowledge that he spit out I I just
wanted all of that and uh before I I
probably talked to him for
over over four months and I had a lot of
questions and things like that so then
after that four months before he left
Cuba I uh I I did what you say I took my
shahada I became Muslim wow and that was
like what was going through your mind
when you decided that you you were going
to go down that path because I mean a
lot you know like cuz I don't know if
you were born Christian or if you had a
religion but like I was I was born
Catholic um I denounced my my my faith
when I was around 20 yeah after watching
a few videos you know when people pass
around the the VHS tapes of like
ministers and stuff like that and I I
was watching a few of the videos and I
decided that I was going to uh that I
would convert into Islam um but uh that
was a big that like at the time that was
a really big step for me um but I I'm I
I don't really I'm more of a agnostic um
agnostic theist so I I just decided I
would just announce everything and I'm
I'm just not that but the the the
decision for me to do it so what like
what were were you scared or were you
excited like what was going through your
mind oh man I was wow back in the days
man like I almost was put in jail in the
military like when I say wow
like I I don't think I've told anybody
this story
and I'm almost ashamed for saying I
almost put the jail in Somalia for
selling tires to the
Somali what like like okay because
here's the entrepreneur
mind we have these tires that were on
these trucks so if a truck was broken
down they would take these tires and
stack them up and then they would burn
the tires later and I'm like holy crap
man you would burn the tires why you
going to burn good tires these people
out here are basically like The
Flintstones you you know basically have
vehicles and they're using their feet
they can use those tires so I was
talking to one of the Somali guards he
said man you would get $95 a piece so
I'm like okay he's going out in the P he
works on the base in a day and he going
out so I literally am talking to this
guy it's probably about 11 o'clock in
the morning pitch dark and I see this
guy in the uniform coming by me I didn't
mean anything I I didn't think anything
cuz we're all a uniform and is he
getting
closer he's my freaking lieutenant and
he heard the whole conversation oh and
saved my life this is what he said he
said uh I w't pretend that I didn't hear
anything you just said because what you
just said to that guy if that would have
took place and you were found if that
they would have found it out you would
have been in jail probably for about 20
years oh so I was
like that was kind of but if he didn't
stop me man I'll been making money in
some
oh
man I've never told that story well you
guys got an exclusive on the hustle Zone
this is
amazing yeah that's crazy so yeah so
back to the question were you scared to
convert were you you know what was going
through your mind when you decided that
you were going to make that decision I I
think the biggest thing for me man was
like am I going to be a good Muslim
because I said I was crazy yeah you know
I was always partying and all this other
kind of stuff now I was going to like go
from that to like I'm not doing anything
um so that's the biggest thing I was
focusing on was like am I going to be
able to do
this
that's that's probably the the biggest
thing I was thinking about wow that's
crazy so where can we find you my friend
okay well you can go to YouTube and find
um and and type in how to find your
passion now my channel will come up I
have a lot of videos over there um you
can find me at Abdul S muhamad I have a
page there and then I als I'm all over
the place then I also have a a page
called the 5 a.m book club uh send a
request friend request and we'll let you
in and uh we talk over there and then uh
the marketing strategy TV is something
that we're doing now and uh we're going
to do something every Thursday so you
can find me there also nice nice yeah
and is there anything else that you want
to leave before you
uh uh before before we end this
broadcast yeah man uh just real quick
guys if you have any ideas if you have
that itch if you suck at your job if you
suck at many jobs don't be afraid of
this
lifestyle um it's going to beat you up
but sometimes we need to be beat up in
life in order to take things to the next
level it just means that you know
failures they say the average
millionaire failed uh 16 to 17 times
before they became a millionaire so
failure is not registered as a bad thing
it just means that you don't have enough
information at that time to complete
that task that you're trying to do
that's all it is so learn more
information and you can complete it so
just just do what you love if that's
what you want to be as an entrepreneur
don't let anyone stop you go after it
well nice well that's folks that's
that's what this this hustle zone is all
about you know everybody has a different
story but you know we do we all have
like I have to like I always say this at
the end of the the the hustle zones but
you know I got to change it up a little
bit we all have different stories but we
all have the same
habits you know we all have the same
like entrepreneurs have the same habits
because things that you said today is
stuff that I do it's stuff that every
other entrepreneur does uh when
especially when they're talking on the
hustle zone so it's it's a it's I want
to thank you so much Abdul for for
coming in here and sharing your story
you know sharing your first
name
BR I got a lot out of you so I I really
I I feel honored I feel blessed folks
you know if there's anything that you
can take away Follow Your Passion you
know a lot of of you are not doing what
is in your heart you know what Abdul is
saying is take some time
meditate realize that your body already
knows what it wants to do when you wake
up and you say well what's my purpose to
life it should be to
be you know be your true self let your
light shine you know just be yourself
and a lot of us you know I I say at the
end of the hustle zone is that there's
two Rel reltionship that you should have
one with
yourself and the other one with your
pillow because they're both important
because you got to sleep at night you
got to sleep you got to sleep and you
have to sleep with the empty conscience
and if you're not doing things that you
are passionate about you know you're not
going to you're not going to have sleeps
right so you know the most important
thing is to get to know yourself so that
you can sleep better at night and do
things and and lead the charge live the
life that you were destined to live you
know I'm not saying that your life was
predetermined because you could draw
maybe that's not what but even if you
follow your passion you might find other
things that will also be a part of your
passion so Abdul thank you so much for
coming into the hustle Zone and can you
do that hustle Zone Thing One More
Time welcome to the hustle
Zone thank you so much